here's a seven exercise mini bed blue
circuit that you can do before or after
your workout if you do it before your
workout for glute activation I wouldn't
go quite as far you can complete the
sets and reps just don't push yourself
as hard if you do at the end as part of
the burnout then you can do a harder and
you can do maybe two or three rounds
over time but I'd start out doing one
round now I have too many bands here but
you can use a hip circle you can give
you the mini bands come in different
strengths and sizes so you have to learn
how to modify the exercise according to
your bands but the bands that you'll
likely have ones like these and if if
you have one that's strong enough in one
band will suffice but you can also
double up on them or you can put them in
different positions so I'll show you
that in a minute
so the first exercise is the glute
bridge so notice here that I have two
different mini bands I've got one above
the knees that one below you can have
you can on both of them above both below
want to eat or just that one band just
depends on your straight but I'm
actually gonna use these two options are
you just do a wide stance like this the
whole time or you can kind of do a
narrow stance with it applicable time so
that's up to you
I encourage you to try both let's see
what you like the most but it takes a
lot of glute strength to just hold the
bands out what you're gonna do is drive
your elbows in the ground tuck your chin
if you have poor neck endurance you can
write down but tuck your chin
here lift your toes up 1 1 2 3 1 2 3 so
3 second puzzle the top 1 2 3 then I'm
pushing out the whole time 1 2 3 and
then 10 reps total so that's it just
says one next step is the squat and we
have a pause in the glute bridge at the
top this one we're going to hold the
positive bottom so safety to 10 reps
with a three-second bust but as I push
my hands forward like this so let me get
a medium stance slight folks where and
then when I go down I'm enforcing the
knees out so it looks like this 1 2 3 1
2 3 and as far as def goes just go to
run parallel next up is the lateral bad
luck so I am going to keep my feet
pointing straight ahead I'm going to
crouch down making sure my shins are
pretty vertical so I sit back and then
from here I'm gonna go take steps left
in the right I'm gonna end up doing 20
steps to the left or X of 40 total steps
so looks like this
now I'm not going to turn my feet out
I'm not gonna let my east gator like
this and I'm not gonna be upright and
let my knees jump forward and I'm not
going to be all sloppy on my reps I'm
not gonna reach with this leg and lean
that way I'm going to stay position
straight ahead and then take little mini
steps keeping my knees out the whole
time and making sure the feet point
straight ahead all right next up is the
quadruped a good extension so I'm going
to be thirty reps per side but I have
two bands here I doubled about to see
that so I got one of the bands
trapped underneath the knee in between
my knee in the ground so it stays in
place and the other side is just behind
the meat so from here I'm getting a good
good position good posture I'm not
rounding over like this I got my chest
up and then from here I'd bend this knee
and then kick straight back one two
three four but I get 20 or sorry thirty
reps of each side and then I switch so
I'll just go up like this and down here
and then switch and then the same thing
on the other side thirty reps and then
you're done right next up is the
standing hip extension abduction
once again I've dug I'm doubling up so
I've got two different bands I like them
above the knees for this I'm actually
gonna hold on to something so I can just
hold on to one of the
right in the rack or I can hold on to
the bar or you go out to both but I'm
going to lean a little bit and then they
keep my link back I'm going to extend an
effort at the same time so it looks like
this one two three four five six seven
feet so I get 3000 mess up and then
switch to get to 30 then you're done
next up is the seated hip abduction so I
got a minivan above the knees and below
the knees but you could just have one or
two of them you could double up above
the little below the experiment to see
what you like best and your stance width
will match the strength of your being so
I'm going to go about here but if you
have a weak band and you only have one
of them you might have to go out live
like this now I just I'm going to do 30
reps leaning back 37 right 30 be leaning
forward but watch how I do it so here
I'm leaning back and I'm going to start
off now notice how I roll to the level
that is my feet I don't flirt might be
out there straight ahead but I roll onto
the ladder edges so 30 reps leading back
then I go upright just up 30 reps this
way and then 30 reps leaning forward and
then finally we have the band hip hinge
abduction so I'm gonna get this would be
a round of shoulder width stance and do
a little bit wider but then I'm going to
sit back my leg would even Romanian
debit so hip hinge so my vertical shins
I don't want to be out like this
drive those knees back need us
shut up lean over it and then feet are
straight ahead
but from here I'm gonna put hands on my
hips I cave in and then I'm going to
force my knees out and I'm gonna roll up
on with the lateral edges of my feet and
a positive three seconds
one two three one two three one two
three
and I'm not gonna come up each rep them
and stay lean like this stay stick your
butt out just like that other set you
need 10-12 reps and then that completes
the surveys once again one round before
the workout is part of glute activation
protocol or you can do one two three
rounds at the end of the workout as part
of the burnout